Common tools and techniques for
identifying the stakeholders.
We'll use expert judgment.
We've seen this over and over.
Ours or team members are SMEs,
experience, expertise.
Just like when you
identify risks, you want as
many people to help
you identify stakeholders.
Anybody, individual group
department organization
that's going to be
impacted by your project.
We'll have meetings.
We'll gather data.
you can send out questionnaires and
surveys, especially if you have a lot of
virtual teams spread out to figure out who
all the stakeholders would be at each
location, for example, and brainstorming
coming up with as many ideas as possible.
Data analysis will do stakeholder analysis
and document analysis.
We are going to look at
any plan, document that is
available, who is going to
be impacted by our project.
Out of them, you'll see
we need to figure out who's
going to impact us, who's
going to be making decisions.
All right, we can use stakeholder mapping,
a way to categorize the stakeholders by
creating a stakeholder grid like power and
interest, power and influence,
influence and impact.
You can create three different grids.
You can create a salience model.
Both of those I will cover, in upcoming
slides.
You can also use a stakeholder cube.
It's a 3D version of the stakeholder grid
with three variables.
And we'll prioritize the stakeholders
themselves based on their power,
interest, and influence.
Directions of influence, similar to
communications that we saw earlier.
Upward to senior management,
downward to the team, sideward
peers within the organization,
out external stakeholders.
Let's look at them in some more detail in
our upcoming lessons.